Scientist Chen Hung Dao.
（ロックスミス）
研究員 チェン･フン･ダオ
Astronaut Christopher Bartholomew.
航宙士
クリストファー･バーソロミュー
Astronaut Eirand Hammer.
航宙士 エイランド･ハマー
機関整備士 ヒューバート･ハイム
Engineer Hubert Heim.
Engineer Leonov Norstein.
機関整備士
レオーノフ･ノルシュテイン
Assistant Navigator James Biko.
副航法員 ジェームズ･ビコ
And next to him are EVA specialist
Sally Silverstone...
その隣 船外活動員
サリー･シルバーストーン
...and fellow EVA specialist Hoshino Hachirota.
同じく船外活動員 星野(ほしの)八郎太(はちろうた)
These 18 men and women are the
Von Braun's handpicked crew.
（ロックスミス）以上 18名が―
フォン･ブラウン号の
選抜クルーです
These are the best of the best, culled from a pool...
彼らは ２万人の候補者の中から
８か月かけて選び抜いた精鋭です
...of some 20,000 applicants over a period of eight months.
With their selection, the crew of the Von Braun is now complete.
これで フォン･ブラウン号の
クルーが全員 決定しました
これほどのメンバーを
今 こうして―
To have the honor of introducing crew members of their caliber to you today...
木星への最初の挑戦者として
ご紹介できるということに―
...as the first humans to challenge Jupiter fills me with joy that I can hardly contain.
私は感動を禁じえません
The Jovian system development project that they will be undertaking...
彼らの担う
木星圏開発計画こそが―
我々 人類の更なる発展を促し―
...will spur humanity's development to new heights,
偉大なる功績として 後世にも
語り継がれていくことでしょう
...and I am sure that tales of their great deeds will be handed down to future generations.
（サリー）ハチマキ ハチマキ
Hachimaki...
ハチマキ！
Hachimaki!
（ハチマキ）ああ
（サリー）ボケッとしない
Stop spacing out!
A reporter is asking you a question.
記者さんが あんたに質問してるよ
（ハチマキ）ああ
（記者）もう一度 お聞きします
前人未到の木星―
I'll repeat the question.
Do you have any worries at all over this long journey of seven years to Jupiter,
それも７年という長旅に
不安はありませんか？
...a planet where no one has gone before?
（シャッター音）
（記者たちのざわめき）
あっ…
Oh. Um...
（記者）ああ… えーっと
Can we assume that it's because of your father that you decided to go to Jupiter?
木星へ行くことを決めたのは
やはり お父さんの影響が？
（ハチマキ）行く？ どこに？
Go? Go where?
はあ？
（ハチマキ）
どこに行くんだ？ 俺は
Where am I going?
えっ？
（記者たちのざわめき）
（レオーノフ）ハハハハ…
This guy's jokes aren't very funny, are they?
こいつのジョーク
笑えないでしょう？
Our biggest worry on this project is that we'll have to listen to his jokes for seven years.
このジョークを
７年間も聞かされ続けるのが―
この計画の
最大の不安ってやつです
（記者たちの笑い声）
（ハチマキ）ああ…
♪～
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪幾千の朝に
♪光が向かう場所へ
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪フロンティアへ
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
Phase 25
The Lost
（レオーノフ）ハチマキ
C'mon, Hachimaki, I wish you wouldn't say weird stuff like that.
あんまり変なこと
言わないでくれよな
せっかくの
晴れ舞台なんだし
Gala occasions like that don't happen every day, you know?
（サリー）あの事件以来
おかしいよ あんた
You've been acting funny ever since the attack.
Are you sure you shouldn't go see the doctor?
医者にかかったほうが
いいんじゃない？
I've passed all my medical checks.
医療チェックはクリアしてる
体のほうじゃなくてさあ その…
It's not your body I'm worried about. It's, well...
（レオーノフ）まあ
あしたからは久しぶりの休暇だ
Hey, our first vacation in ages is gonna start tomorrow.
思いっ切り 羽伸ばしてこいよ
Go have yourself a good time before you come back, you hear?
Yeah, try to have some fun!
そうそう 気分転換 図りな
（レオーノフ）しっかし―
Still, I can't believe how far the repairs have come here,
宇宙防衛戦線が襲撃してきてから
まだ半年だってのに―
...even though it's only been six months since the Space Defense Front attack.
よく ここまで直したもんだよな
クルーのお披露目までには
間に合わせるって―
Looks like Galileo Development worked themselves to the bone...
ガリレオ開発が
強引に動いたみたい
...to have it ready before the crew's debut.
That President Dolf of theirs is a real piece of work.
あのドルフって社長さん
大したやり手だな
（たたく音）
（サリー）ん？
（レオーノフ）あ？
おいおい 虫だよ 虫
Are you kidding me?
Check it out, it's a bug!
誰が持ち込んだの？
衛生部に連絡しないと
Who brought them on board?
We'd better contact the sanitation department.
せっかく ７年間は―
Damn, and here I thought I could kiss bugs goodbye for a whole seven years...
虫とおさらばできると
思ったのによ もう
検疫体制はどうなってんだ？
What's up with the quarantine procedures around here?
Congratulations to Hometown Astronauts Goro and Hachirota Hoshino!
（ハルコ）はあ？ フフフッ
（女性）星野さん おめでとう
Hoshino-san, congratulations!
Goodness... I'm used to seeing things like that for my husband, but not my son.
So, what're you gonna do on your vacation, Sally?
（レオーノフ）…で
休暇はどうするんだよ サリー
Me?
（サリー）
私？ うーん 地球(オカ)に降りてね
Hm... I'm gonna go back to Earth and have a picnic!
ピクニック
A picnic?
ピクニック？
そう テムズ川の川辺でね
Yeah, on the bank of the Thames.
へえ 顔に似合わず
意外とかわいいところ…
You'd never guess it from your face, but you've got a girlish side...
- Leonov!
（男性）レオーノフ
You're a celebrity now, so watch what you say and do.
もう有名人なんだから
言動には気をつけろよ
Yeah, yeah...
（レオーノフ）はいはい
Hey, Leo! Have you seen my son around?
（ゴロー）おい レオ
俺の息子 見なかったか？
え？
If you're looking for Hachi, he came here on the flight before ours.
ハチなら
私たちより先の便でこちらに
Geez, I should've known...
（ゴロー）あー やっぱ そうか
Where'd that kid go?
どーこ行っちゃったんだ あいつ
（社員１）ああ 待って
そのデータは一旦―
Just a minute. They said to put those files in the folder on the server for now.
サーバーのフォルダーに
入れておいてって
Aren't we going to transmit them to Technora?
（社員２）テクノーラに
送信するんじゃないのか？
President Dolf's orders. I don't know the details, but it's probably a security issue.
（社員１）ドルフ社長の命令
よく知らないけど
セキュリティーの問題でしょ？
Even so, all these complicated procedures are getting out of hand.
（社員２）…にしても
複雑な手続きが増えすぎだ
I bet President Dolf is the only one who has access to all the information...
全部の情報を把握してるのって
ドルフ社長だけなんじゃないか？
（警告音）
An O2 depletion alarm? From a spacesuit?
（社員１）酸欠警報？ 宇宙服の？
乗組員は休暇中だろ？
Aren't all the crew on vacation?
反応は… 月面から？
The signal's... coming from the lunar surface?
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
Rescue Command, this is Rescue 42.
（隊員）
救難本部 こちら レスキュー42
要救助者を発見
We've found the subject.
救難本部 こちら レスキュー42
Rescue Command, this is Rescue 42.
We've found the subject.
要救助者を発見
こちら救難本部
This is Rescue Command.
（隊員１）星野！
星野八郎太だな？ 聞こえるか？
Hoshino? You're Hoshino Hachirota, right?
Can you hear me?
Yeah...
ああ…
（隊員）しっかりしろ
こんな所で２日も何やってたんだ
Pull yourself together!
What have you been doing out here for two days?!
Geez, if you hadn't been wearing one of the
Von Braun's custom suits, you'd be dead.
まったく…
フォン･ブラウン用の装備でなきゃ
死んでるぞ
ああ ほんとだ
Yeah, you're right...
ああっ
Anyway, let me replenish your O2.
とにかく 酸素を補充します
Open up the cartridge on your back.
後ろのカートリッジを開いて
帰ったら すぐに
精密検査を受けてもらうから
When we get back, I'm sending you in for a complete checkup, got it?
Get back? Back where? How?
（ハチマキ）
帰る？ どこへ？ どうやって？
Okay, Cheng-Shin.
（船長）おい チェンシン
You haven't carried passengers in a while, so make sure you're good and nervous.
久しぶりに
人を乗せているんだから
思いっ切り緊張しろよ
Yes, sir. I understand.
（チェンシン）
はい 分かっています
この度は 本船をご利用いただき
誠にありがとうございます
Thank you for choosing to fly with us today.
航行に際しまして
お客さまへのお願いを申し上げます
We ask that our passengers follow the following rules while we are en route.
（ロックスミス）
社長さん 星野親子をどうした？
Mr. President!
Where are the Hoshinos?
I sent them back to Earth.
（ドルフ）地球(オカ)に戻しました
Hoshino Hachirota is in need of R&R.
星野八郎太には 休養が必要です
Then you could have sent the son by himself, couldn't you?
（ロックスミス）だったら
息子だけ降ろせばいいだろう？
父親同伴なんて
The father didn't need to go with him!
（ドルフ）
これは その父親の希望です
It was a request from the father.
（ロックスミス）ええっ？
（ドルフ）星野八郎太は
訓練の継続を望んだのですが―
Hoshino Hachirota wanted to continue with his training,
...but Hoshino Goro said that he would take him back to Earth personally.
星野ゴローが
自分が連れて降りると
（ロックスミス）うーん…
Actually, Dr. Locksmith, there is another matter that I'd like to discuss with you.
それより ロックスミス博士
折り入って
ご相談したいことがあります
（ロックスミス）
何です？ 怖い顔して
What is it? You look awfully serious.
Oh, you'll have to forgive me, but it's an important matter...
ああ すみません
大事な話なもので
（アナウンス）
スケジュール調整のため―
Our flight has been delayed due to schedule adjustments.
遅れております
出発まで１時間遅れとなります
Our departure will be one hour behind schedule.
（ゴロー）
おいおい まいったよなあ
Are you kidding me? Oh, man...
乗り換えに １時間待ちなんてよう
We've got an hour layover before our connecting flight... You hear?
なっ？
こっちは変装しなきゃいけない
有名人だってのに なあ？
And here we are, two celebrities who have to travel incognito...
You know?
あっ アハハ
Oh, hey, I know!
I'll go buy us something to drink!
その… おっ そうだ
飲みもんでも買ってくるよ
ハチ お前 何がいい？
Hachi, what do you want?
Some sake, right?
じゃ 酒な 決まり つきあえよ
You're on!
You better keep up with me!
That's okay, I'll...
いや 俺は…
あ…
（男性）そう テクノーラ
That's right, Technora!
Which way do I go to get to Technora?
テクノーラ社ってのは
どう行けばいいんだ？
To reach Technora, please use the elevator that's four blocks ahead...
（案内係）
テクノーラ社でしたら―
４ブロック先のエレベーターで
企業フロアに向かってください
...and take it to the business floor.
You can find their reception desk there.
そちらに受付がありますので
Got it. Four blocks ahead, right?
（男性）
分かった ４ブロック先だな
おっ
That stupid kid...
あの野郎…
Geez, Tanabe's still using this desk after all this time?
（ハチマキ）何だよ タナベのやつ
今でも ここ使ってんのか
Come to think of it, what did I write in my own will?
（ハチマキ）
俺 自分の遺言状に何て書いたっけ
Well, I'll be! It's Ha-chan!
（課長）
あれ ハッちゃんじゃない？
Hey, if you were coming, you should've let us know.
（ラビィ）何だよ
来るなら言ってくれればいいのに
（課長）すごいね ハッちゃん
テレビで見たよ
That was amazing, Hachi!
I saw you on TV!
ほんと 立派になったねえ
You've really made something of yourself!
あっ ちょっと待ってろ
今 フィー君たち 呼んでくるから
Right! Wait here, I'll call
Fee-kun and the others!
組合の会議だっけ？
Aren't they at the union meeting?
ええ ほら クレアさんも
タナベ君もいなくなって―
Right!
See, ever we lost Claire-san and Tanabe-kun, we've been awfully shorthanded around here.
人手が足りなくてさあ
いない？
She left?
あっ 知らなかったっけ？
You didn't know?
そっか その…
Oh, right! Um...
タナベ君は帰ったんだ 地球(オカ)に
Tanabe-kun went home.
Back to Earth.
Ai-chan went through a lot of things, and she ended up resigning from the company.
（課長）
愛(あい)ちゃん いろいろあってさ―
辞めることになったんだ 会社
She quit.
W-Well, she's still young!
ま… まあ 彼女は まだ若いしさ
She can always start again from scratch.
いくらでもやり直しが利くし
ハハハハハ…
Here are Tanabe-kun's address and phone number.
これ タナベ君の住所と電話番号
えっ？
She pretended that everything was okay, but she wanted to go see you, Ha-chan.
（課長）
大丈夫なふりしてたけど―
会いたがってたよ ハッちゃんに
Go pay her a visit before you leave for Jupiter. Okay?
木星に行く前に一度くらい
なっ？
（ハチマキ）あ…
（ゴロー）182センチ！？
182 centimeters?!
…てことは
あー 月平均 1,75センチ！？
Let's see, that works out to an average of... um, 1.75cm a month!
You're growing like a weed, boy...
非常識な成長しやがって
もっと地球のこととか考えて生きろ
Show a little more consideration for the Earth when you're living down here!
…ていうか もう食うな
Or more to the point, quit eating.
お前のカツは
俺がなんとかしてやる
I'll take those pork cutlets off your hands.
You're not making any sense, old man.
You should be happy that your son is growing.
（九太郎(きゅうたろう)）
わけ分かんねえな このおっさんは
素直に息子の成長を喜べよ
育ち過ぎだってんだよ
You're growing too big, is my point.
Here you go, Hachi.
You should eat up, too.
おい ハチ お前も食え
We won't be able to have these for the next seven years.
俺たちは７年間
食えなくなるんだぞ
You don't have to let Kyu have 'em all.
キュウに遠慮することはない
兄貴は
とっくに成長期 終わってるだろ
Hachi quit growing a long time ago.
And while we're at it, don't act like hot stuff just 'cause you're going to Jupiter!
大体 木星に行くからって
偉そうにすんな
俺は
あんたらが帰ってくるまでに―
By the time you two get back from Jupiter,
I'm gonna build a ship to go to Venus!
金星に行く船を
造ってやるんだから
- What're you spouting?
（ゴロー）何言ってやがる
そもそも このカツは―
It was money that I earned that put those pork cutlets on your plate.
どうしたの？ ハチ
What's the matter, Hachi?
俺が働いた金で…
（九太郎）あっ そう
If you don't eat faster, they'll take them all.
俺が働いた金で…
（九太郎）あっ そう
ちゃっちゃと食べないと
取られちゃうよ
- Gee, really?
ちゃっちゃと食べないと
取られちゃうよ
Yeah, really.
ちゃっちゃと食べないと
取られちゃうよ
（ゴロー）
〝あっ そう〞とは何だい
ああ… もういいや
ここまで
大きくなれたのは―
Who do you think you have to thank for growing so big, huh, boy?
That's okay.
ああ… もういいや
誰のおかげだと
思ってんだ？ こら
えっ？
I'm done.
（ハチマキ）ごちそうさん
（九太郎）ん？
（戸の開く音）
Their pitcher, Iketani, had a string of injuries last season.
（ハルコ）ハチ 何かあったの？
Did something happen to Hachi?
（ゴロー）
あったんじゃねえのかなあ
I dunno, maybe something did happen...
What do you think, Uchida? What's your opinion after seeing the season this far?
（ハルコ）何？ それ
What's that mean?
（ゴロー）
いや よく分かんねえんだよ
I'm not really sure.
At first, I thought he had that bug that sailors always catch that's like the measles,
最初は 船乗りがよくかかる
はしかみたいなもんだと思って―
放っといたんだが
...so I let him be, but...
（ハルコ）大丈夫なの？
Will he be all right?
ハルコさんのトンカツ食べりゃ
なんとかなると思ったんだがなあ
I'd thought he might snap out of it if he had some of your pork cutlets, but, well...
ちょっと深刻ねえ
It sounds serious.
Yeah, I wonder what happened to him?
（ゴロー）
ああ… どうしたもんかなあ
あっ
しまった
Oops. I accidentally left the office with it...
持ってきちゃったよ これ
ああ…
ヘッ どうせ 愛がどうとか書いて…
It's just gonna have a bunch of stuff about "love" in it, anyway...
Last Will
あっ… あ…
（エンジンのかかる音）
（エンジンの音）
ん？
ん…
I-I'm Tanabe, I just started here!
（タナベ）あっ し… 新入社員の
タナベと言います
先輩みたいな おむつ男には
分からないかもしれませんけど
Maybe a diaper man like you wouldn't understand that, Senpai.
気合い入れてくださいよ 先輩
C'mon, Senpai!
Let's see some spirit!
できた！
I did it! Senpai, I did it!
先輩 できました！
I-I'm so sorry! I just assumed...
ご… ごめんなさい 私 てっきり…
You're renting a place in
Arnould Area, too, Senpai?
先輩もアルノ地区に
家 借りてるんですか？
だって 私の先生は先輩でしょ？
Well, you're my sensei, right, Senpai?
こういうのに
新入りも先輩もないと思います
I don't think this is a time for worrying about who's a rookie or who's a Senpai!
駄目です 書き直し！
This is no good! Rewrite it!
I knew you were rude and violent, but I didn't think you were capable of this, Senpai!
先輩が がさつで乱暴なのは
分かってましたけど―
まさか こんなことするなんて！
That's why I'm saying that you've got no delicacy!
そういうところが
デリカシーに欠けるっていうんです
愛です！
I'll leave them love!
Look at that will you wrote!
You're the one with the problem!
先輩なんて―
あんな遺言状 書いてるから
いけないんですよ
どうして 分からないんですか？
Why can't you understand?!
We can't send this man back into space!
この人は
宇宙に返しちゃ駄目なんです！
そんなんじゃありません
私は先輩が…
It's not like that at all!
I was worried that you might...
あの…
それって どういう意味ですか？
Um... What do you mean by that?
出てます？ 私の目から
Are they shooting out? Of my eyes, I mean.
次 先輩の番ですよ
私 言ったんですから
Now it's your turn, Senpai.
I told you, so now you go!
単純ですね
That's a simple reason.
No, it's your style.
It's just what you'd expect.
いえ 先輩らしいです とっても
How is he?!
Is he going to be all right?!
先輩は…
先輩は大丈夫なんですか？
よかった ほんと よかった
Thank goodness... I'm so relieved...
うるさーいっ！
Shut up!
待って！
Wait, don't go!
聞きたいことも話したいことも
いっぱいあるんです
There's so much that I want to ask you and talk to you about!
会社を辞めるのも
フォン･ブラウンに乗るのも―
You decided all on your own to quit the company and to try out for the Von Braun.
１人でさっさと決めちゃって
I wanted you to tell me about it.
To talk to me about it...
言ってほしかった
話してほしかったのに
私 先輩のこと…
（八郎太）
おい 後悔してるのか？ まさか
Hey, you aren't having second thoughts, are you?
（ハチマキ）うっ
Man, you're weak. You're still trying to turn to others for help?
（八郎太）甘いんだよ
今更 誰かにすがろうなんて
前にも言ったろ？
人間は 所詮 １人だって
I told you before, didn't I?
In the end, all humans are alone.
（ハチマキ）ああ そうだな １人だ
Yeah, I guess I am. I'm alone.
I'm really alone, aren't I?
１人 なんだよな？
You're right, I'm...
そうだ 俺は…
（ハチマキ）あっ
（急ブレーキの音）
（衝突音）
（ハチマキ）えっ
Hey, wait a minute!
（ハチマキ）えっ おい ちょっと…
ああっ…
何だ？ ここ
What is this place?
何もない
There's nothing... Nothing at all.
死んだのか？
Am I dead?
いや 生きてる それだけは分かる
No, I'm alive.
That's the one thing I'm sure of.
でも… 何もない
But...
There's nothing here... I'm alone.
１人だ
１人だけ
It's just me...
そうだよ
俺が そう言ったんじゃないか
That's right, that's exactly what I said, isn't it?
俺が そう望んだんじゃないか
That's exactly what I wanted, isn't it?
でも…
But...
Not here... Not like this...
ここは…
ここじゃ…
Somebody!
誰か うわっ
誰かーっ！
Somebody!
ああっ
あ… ああっ
あっ
That's right, this is what you wanted.
（ハキム）
そうだ お前が望んだんだ
Shoot, and fall into the abyss.
撃てよ そして修羅に落ちるがいい
Sure, I'll shoot.
ああ 撃つさ
I'll shoot, and then I'll...
撃って 俺は…
No ammo?
（ハチマキ）弾切れ！？ くっ
（ハキム）えいっ
あっ くっ
Hakim! Don't act like you know it all!
ハキム
分かってるような顔すんな！
（ハキム）うわっ ぐわあーっ
（ハチマキ）ぐあっ ううっ
（ハチマキ）
口先だけの決意じゃなかった
My determination wasn't all talk.
（ハチマキ）断ち切るつもりだった
I really did intend to put an end to it.
殺すつもりだった
I really intended to kill him.
But...
けど 弾が出なかったんだ
the gun didn't fire.
俺は引き金を引いたのに
I pulled the trigger, but the gun didn't fire.
俺のせいじゃない
It isn't my fault.
じゃあ 誰のせいだ？
Whose is it, then?
Whose fault? No, what do I have to thank for it?
撃たずに済んだのは
何のおかげだ？
What do I owe my thanks to for not having to shoot him?
But I...
でも 俺は…
Come on, Senpai, let's go home.
（タナベ）
先輩 もう帰りましょ
あっ… あっ
タナベ
Tanabe?
Let's go home, Senpai.
帰りましょう 先輩
あっ ああっ…
（フィー）
何やってんだよ バカハチ
What're you waiting for, dummy Hachi?
あっ
Let's go, Hachimaki.
（ユーリ）行こう ハチマキ
I'll leave you to it, Ha-chan!
頼むよ ハッちゃん
Hachi, didn't I tell you that nobody gets overtime?
ハチ 残業はなしだって言ったろ？
It's quitting time.
（エーデル）時間ですので
You never change, do you, Hachi?
（クレア）相変わらずね ハチ
I know you can do it, Hachi.
ハチならやれるさ
Right, Hachimaki?
Hachimaki...
（ギガルト）ハチマキ
Take it nice and easy, there's no rush.
ゆっくりでいい
ゆっくり ゆっくりだ
（ゴロー）
何やってんだ？ バカ息子
What're you doing, you dumb kid?
（九太郎）兄ちゃん
中途半端にカッコつけんなよ
Don't act big when your job's not done yet, nii-chan.
（ハルコ）
ハチ ごはん なくなっちゃうよ
Hachi, the food will all be gone.
（一同）ハチ ハチ ハチ ハチ…
（ハチマキのせき込み）
ああっ ハァハァ…
ああっ ううっ… ハァ ハァ…
（ハチマキ）あ… あれが…
That...
あれが宇宙？
That was space?
じゃあ
今の今まで俺が見ていた宇宙は―
If what I just saw was space, then what the hell have I been looking at up until now?
一体 何だったんだ
（タナベ）
あの 大丈夫ですか？
Excuse me, are you all right?
あっ
ああ？
先輩？
Senpai?
ハチマキ先輩？
Hachimaki Senpai?
えっ？
Senpai?!
先輩！
Is that really you?!
ほんとに先輩なんですか？
先輩のバイクは―
I'll have my dad go get your bike later.
（タナベ）あとで 父にでも
取りに行ってもらいますから
Thanks. Sorry about that.
（ハチマキ）ああ 悪いな
Oh, that reminds me. I went all the way to the Von Braun to see you, Senpai.
そうそう 私―
フォン･ブラウン号まで
先輩に会いに行ったんですよ
Hey, the ship's off-limits to unauthorized personnel...
（ハチマキ）
関係者以外 立ち入り禁止だぞ
I cheated a little.
I asked Colin-san to help me.
（タナベ）
ちょっと ずるしたんです
コリンさんにお願いして
Colin? You mean that idiot son of the INTO chairman?
（ハチマキ）
コリンって 議長のバカ息子か？
（タナベ）
今は連合の監査官なんですって
He says he works for INTO as an inspector now.
（ハチマキ）へえ
（タナベ）呼び出しを
お願いしているときに―
Just as we were asking them to call for you,
we got caught up in that big mess.
あの事件に巻き込まれちゃって
（ハチマキ）そうか
You did?
タナベ ひょっとして その足
宇宙防衛戦線に？
Tanabe?
Your legs didn't get hurt in the
Space Defense Front attack, did they?
あっ… いえ
すぐに脱出しましたから
No, I escaped right away.
だけど 不時着した所が
有人施設から離れすぎていて
But the place where I came down was too far away from a manned facility.
ＳＯＳは？
What about an SOS?
I sent one out, but nobody answered.
（タナベ）
出したけど 応答がなくって―
しかたないから
歩くことにしたんですけど―
I didn't have any choice, so I started to walk.
But my O2 ran out on the way there.
途中で酸素がなくなっちゃって
（ハチマキ）それで
And that's how...
（タナベ）はい
Right.
通りかかったシャトルバスに
助けてもらって
I was rescued by a shuttle bus that happened to be passing by.
But I suffered nerve damage from the oxygen deprivation,
でも 酸素不足で
神経がやられちゃって―
ナノナーブズカプラー手術って
難しい治療 受けて
...and I underwent a tricky procedure called a "nano nerve coupler" operation.
ああ 覚えちゃいました 医学用語
Hey, I remembered the medical lingo!
さっきも自分でリハビリを…
I was out here doing my rehabilitation exercises.
お医者さんからも
きちんと頑張れば元に戻れるって
The doctors say that if I work hard at it,
I'll make a full recovery.
そうか
They did, huh?
はい
Right.
実際 クレアさんは
すぐに退院しましたし
Actually, Claire-san was discharged from the hospital right away.
クレア？
Claire?
Oh. She escaped from the ship with me.
あっ 一緒に脱出したんです
クレアさんのほうが 酸素の消費が
少なかったみたいで―
Apparently, she had been using a lot less O2 than I was.
There was less damage to her brain.
脳へのダメージも
軽度だったんです
私は もっとリハビリに
時間がかかりそうだったし―
It sounded to me like my rehabilitation would take a long time,
...and since I didn't even know if I'd recover,
I submitted a letter of resignation.
治るかどうかも分からなかったから
会社には辞表を
そっか
You did?
ええ
Yeah...
（ハチマキ）そっか
Oh.
Tanabe...
（ハチマキ）タナベ 俺 お前に―
There's something that
I need to apologize to you for.
謝らなくちゃならないことが
あるんだ
無断で読んだ
I read this without asking.
So I thought I should apologize.
だから 謝ろうと思って
I shouldn't have.
悪かった
あっ…
去年は ちゃんと書いたんです
I wrote out a proper will last year.
“育ててくれて
ありがとう”とか―
It said stuff like "Thank you for raising me,"
and "Goodbye," and "I'm sorry"...
“さようなら”とか
“ごめんなさい”とか
でも 実際に
宇宙でいろんなことを経験して―
They told me to write out another one this year,
先輩もいなくなって…
...but after all the things I'd experienced firsthand out in space, and with you gone,
今年 また
新しく書けって言われたら―
何も書けなくて…
...I couldn't write anything.
先輩に さんざん言ったくせに
And after all those things I said to you...
でも どんな言葉も違う気がして
But nothing that I wrote felt right to me...
そうか
Oh...
Tanabe... When we ran into each other a minute ago,
タナベ さっき お前に会ったとき
分かった気がするんだ
...I think I figured something out.
（タナベ）あっ…
（ハチマキ）俺の宇宙ってさ
ちっぽけだったんだよ
My idea of space was too small.
Sure, there's a lot of painful stuff and questions without answers,
確かに いろんな悩みや
答えが出ないことって―
いっぱいあるんだけど だけどさ
...but there's nothing in this world that isn't part of space.
この世に 宇宙の一部じゃないもの
なんてなくって―
I realized that even I'm connected to it.
That those connections are what make up space.
俺ですら つながっていて
それで初めて宇宙なんだって
（タナベ）あっ…
I realized that maybe I'm okay with that.
なんか それでいいのかなって
ハハッ うまく言えないな
I can't really explain it.
だけど タナベも それが
言いたかったんじゃないのか？
But that's what you were trying to tell me, wasn't it?
この世界は 全てつながってるって
That everything in this world is connected.
そして それをつなげているのが…
And the thing that binds it all together is...
♪～
♪グッと水を飲み干し
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
♪～
Next Time
And The Days We Chance Upon...